PUSPA RAJ KHANAL

(603) 660 - 1535 Khanalpr29@gmail.com

Accomplished, team-oriented and meticulous software engineer with 4+ years of experience in software development. Highly experienced in modern cloud technologies, data analytics and microservice based application development. More than two years of experience working in DevOps setting.

SKILLS

Programming: Java, Python, C#, R

Web: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Cloud: AWS, PCF

API Management: Google APIGEE

Databases: Oracle, MSSQL, InfluxDB, DynamoDB

Containers: Kubernetes, Rancher, Docker

Messaging: Kafka

Caching: Aerospike

• Frameworks: Spring Boot, Hibernate, MyBatis

CI/CD: Concourse, Jenkins, Artifactory, GitHub

Unit & Load Testing: Junit, JMeter

• Others: DevOps, Microservice architecture, Data

Analytics. Swagger, Json, Yaml

EXPERIENCE

01/2018 - PRESENT

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, FIDELITY INVESTMETNTS, MERRIMACK, NH

- Built capabilities and automation patterns using AWS, Concourse, Python and Docker to migrate hundreds of applications to the cloud as part of initial cloud migration team.
- Provided support and technical guidance to different teams within Fidelity to support the cloud migration process.
- Integrated and rolled out APIGEE SaaS platform with enterprise grade API security.
- Designed and developed REST APIs using APIGEE, created shared flows and build automation pattern for creating and deploying APIGEE proxy and products to be used by hundreds of developers across the company.
- Built messaging application for transferring live date between applications using Kafka, Aerospike and Spring Boot. The application was exponentially faster than the legacy messaging applications of the company.
- Currently working in building next generation brokerage platform using all the latest and greatest technologies which will ultimately replace the fidelity's legacy brokerage application.
- $\bullet \qquad \hbox{Performed load testing of the applications using Apache JMeter}.$
- Converted SOAP based applications to RESTful Spring Boot microservice applications.

06/2017 - 12/2017

IT SYSTEM SUPPORT ANALYST, GRANITE STATE COLLEGE, CONCORD, NH

- Configured and maintained LMS application of the college.
- Supported the product development by solving the production issues.
- Assisted with the installation of new hardware and software and help train employees on its use.
- Offered suggestions and implementations for possible upgrades and changes within the IT department.
- Prepared technical documentation for past and ongoing IT projects.

03/2015 - 06/2016

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, CUBIC TECHNOLOGIES, IRVING, TX

- Developed Java based web application using frameworks including Spring, Hibernate, JSF.
- Designed databases, developed SQL queries, stored procedures and views data manipulation and transaction.
- Worked on solving production support issues on multiple occasions.
- Wrote effective unit tests using Junit

03/2013 - 12/2013

CAD TECHNICIAN/TECHNICAL SUPPORT ANALYST, AEROLOGICS, NASHUA, NH

- Designed and drafted the roof of the house based on the aerial image using company's design software.
- Provided technical support to the customer and offshore team members.
- Provided upgrades and enhancements to the application as needed to support various customer demands.

EDUCATION

12 /2017

BS IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, GRANITE STATE COLLEGE, CONCORD, NH (G.P.A 3.8)

09/2019 - 06/2021

MS IN APPLIED DATA ANALYTICS, BOSTON UNIVERSITY, BOSTON, MA